Chuanqi Tan

CONTACT Information State Key Laboratory of Intelligent Technology and Systems

Computer Science and Technology, Tsinghua University, Beijing, China

Email: tcq15@mails.tsinghua.edu.cn

Mobile: +86 15210503230 Homepage: www.chuanqi.name

Personal Profile I am a 3rd year Ph.D candidate from Tsinghua University, Beijing, China. I am interested in using deep learning and transfer learning techniques to build better biological information system. The biggest problem hinder the improvement of this area is insufficient training data. Compared to other signals, the collection of biological data is complex and expensive. In my research, I have achieved encouraging experimental results by transfer knowledge from computer vision. In the future, I have planed to improve my research by using advanced transfer learning technologies.

EDUCATION

Tsinghua University

2015-Now

Ph.D. Candidate, Computer Science and Technology Research Fields: Brain Computer Interface, Transfer Learning.

Beijing Institute of Technology

2009-2012

Master, Computer Science and Technology Research Fields: Computer Vision.

Tianjin Polytechnic University

2003-2007

Bachelor, Computer Science and Technology

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

- [1]. Tan, C., Sun, F., & Zhang, W. (2018). Electroencephalography Classification in Brain-Computer Interface with Manifold Constraints Transfer. In The 40th Annual International Conference of the IEEE Engineering in Medicine and Biology Society, EMBC 2018.
- [2]. Tan, C., Sun, F., Zhang, W., & Kong, T. (2018). Adaptive Adversarial Transfer Learning for Electroencephalography Classification. In The International Joint Conference on Neural Networks, IJCNN 2018.
- [3]. Sun, F., Zhang, W., Chen, J., Wu, H., **Tan, C.**, & Su, W. (2018). Fused Fuzzy Petri Nets: a shared control method for Brain Computer Interface systems. IEEE Transactions on Cognitive and Developmental Systems.
- [4]. Tan, C., Sun, F., & Zhang, W. Deep Transfer Learning for EEG-based Brain Computer Interface. 2018 IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing, IEEE ICASSP 2018.
- [5]. Zhang, W., Sun, F., Liu, C., Su, W., Tan, C., & Liu, S. (2017). A hybrid EEG-based BCI for robot grasp controlling. In The 2017 IEEE International Conference on Systems, Man, and Cybernetics, IEEE SMC 2017.
- [6]. Tan, C., Sun, F., Zhang, W., Chen, J., & Liu, C. (2017). Multimodal Classification with Deep Convolutional-Recurrent Neural Networks for Electroencephalography. In The 24th International Conference On Neural Information Processing, ICONIP 2017. Best Student Paper Award.

- [7]. Tan, C., Sun, F., Zhang, W., Liu, S., & Liu, C. (2017). Spatial and spectral features fusion for EEG classification during motor imagery in BCI. In Biomedical & Health Informatics (BHI), 2017 IEEE EMBS International Conference on (pp. 309312). IEEE.
- [8]. Zhang, W., Sun, F., **Tan, C.**, & Liu, S. (2016). Low-Rank Linear Dynamical Systems for Motor Imagery EEG. Computational Intelligence and Neuroscience, 2016.

SUBMITTED PUBLICATIONS

- [1]. **Tan, C.**, Sun, F., Liu, F., & Zhang, W. Beyond Electroencephalography: A Computer Vision Perspective of Brain Computer Interface. Submitted to *IEEE SMC 2018*.
- [2]. **Tan, C.**, Sun, F., & Zhang, W. A Survey on Deep Transfer Learning. Submitted to *ICANN 2018*.

Industry	
EXPERIENCE	

TDRHedu.com, CTO	2015.1-2015.10
Baidu.com, Senior research & develop engineer	2013.10-2015.1
Jike.com, Senior research & develop engineer	2012.1-2013.10